Irv Hagglund Papers
Irv Hagglund Papers
1964-1971
Hagglund, Irvin.
.5 linear ft.
Original art, a few items of correspondence and memorabilia, and published material.
2653483
Biographical History
Irvin (Arvid) Hagglund (1915-1982) was an American cartoonist.
Scope and Contents of the Collection
The Irvin Hagglund Papers contains artwork, a few items of correspondence and memorabilia, and published material.
Artwork contains original cartoons as well as some sketches done on envelopes. The cartoons, all of which are single-panel gag cartoons done in simple black-and-white line art, use general American life for their jokes; there have no particular theme and no recurring characters. Correspondence contains letters from clients, fans, and others. Memorabilia consists of the program for the 1964 Southern California Exposition, in which Hagglund's work appeared. Published material consists largely of clippings of Hagglund's work from various magazines; most are American but there is one folder of clippings of his cartoons that appeared in foreign magazines. There is also a printed placemat-size flier and map for Huckleberry Mountain Workshop Camp, and a copy of Modern Composition which contains a Hagglund cartoon.
Arrangement of the Collection
Alphabetical by title or topic.
Related Material
has collections of over one hundred cartoonists. Please refer to for a complete listing.
Separated Material
Several cartoon anthologies in which Hagglund's work appears were removed from the collection and transferred to Rare Books for cataloging. Please refer to to locate these items.
Subject and Genre Headings
Hagglund, Irvin.; Art -- Cartoonists; American wit and humor, Pictorial.; Caricatures and cartoons -- United States.; Cartoonists -- United States.; United States -- Social life and customs -- Caricatures and cartoons.; Cartoons (humorous images); Correspondence.; Clippings (information artifacts); Sketches.; Cartoonists.
Access Restrictions
The majority of our archival and manuscript collections are housed offsite and require advanced notice for retrieval. Researchers are encouraged to contact us in advance concerning the collection material they wish to access for their research.
Acquisition Information
Gift of Irv Hagglund, 1966 and 1971.
Inventory
- Artwork
  - Original art, miscellaneous, undated (Box 1)
- Correspondence
  - Miscellaneous, 1969-1971 (Box 1)
- Memorabilia
  - Program, Southern California Exposition, 1964 (Box 1)
- Published material
  - Books, Transferred to Rare Books for cataloging, Oct 2009.
  - Clippings, Mexico, undated (pre-1971) (Box 1)
  - Clippings, United States, undated (pre-1971) (Box 1)
  - Clippings, miscellaneous foreign, undated (pre-1971) (Box 1)
  - Miscellaneous, 1969; undated; book, flier (Box 1)